¬
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_APACHEAN_DESCR}Ken Angrok, King of Singhasari\n\nEstimated difficulty: Easy
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_APACHEAN_TITLE}The Outer Islands
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_AZTECS_DESCR}Iztacmixcoatl, Kwāwtlahtoani of the Mexica\n\nEstimated difficulty: ???\n\nTenochtitlan is one of the greatest cities in Mesoamerica. It is formed by the three great cities of Tlacopan, Texcoco, and the capital of Tenochtitlan, and ruled by its emperor, the ‘Hueyi Tlatoani’, or great speaker. Made up of three separate tribes, the Mexica rule over many nearby city-states, enforcing tribute on pain of invasion and sacrifice. \n\nThe Mexica primarily worship Huitzilopochtli, the god of war and of the Sun, who struggles constantly to hold back the darkness and requires nourishment in the form of human sacrifice. The Mexica believe the world may end at the end of a 52 year cycle, which is quickly approaching, unless they can keep Huitzilopochtli strong. It is this need for sacrifices that drives the Mexica to conquest. New territories mean new populations that can be used as slaves and, more importantly, sacrifices to stave off the end of the world. 
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_AZTECS_TITLE}Children of the Sun
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BYZANTIUM_DESCR}Theodōros Komnēnos Laskaris, Emperor of Nicaea\n\nEstimated difficulty: Hard\n\nThe Eastern Roman Empire is the shadow that remains of the old Roman Empire. It is a mere shadow because despite retaining the civilised ways of the Roman legacy, the Eastern Romans have done little to further it. In fact, it is their reverence of the old ways that has brought the empire to a point of stagnation, in a world that has gradually kept moving on. The differences between the thinking in Byzantium and the west were most profoundly highlighted with the Great Schism, the division of Christendom.\n\nDespite boasting the world's trade capital and home of Orthodox Christianity in Constantinople, the Roman Empire is well past its zenith and is now in steady decline. The outer regions of the empire have been slipping from the Basileus's grasp for decades now. To the west, the Normans have taken southern Italy, and in the east the Seljuks have moved into Asia Minor after their decisive and terrible victory at Manzikert. The latter of these two losses was the worst defeat the Empire had suffered in its entire history. To make matters worse, general corruption, chaos and dissent has lead to some of the other provinces closer to home to rebel. \n\nArguably, the greatest threat to Byzantium lies in its independence from Rome. There is significant risk that the lords of the west will consider the lands of Orthodox Christianity to be fair game unless the Pope decrees otherwise. It is a true irony that Constantinople may now have to appease Rome after becoming the new capital of the Roman Empire centuries ago.\n\nIf the Roman Empire is to once again become the dominant power of Europe, then it will first need to reclaim its heartlands wholly before encroaching upon the borders of another power. The Roman legacy is long and predominantly proud, but unless the Basileus can turn things around in a hurry, it is a legacy that will soon end.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BYZANTIUM_TITLE}A Fallen Eagle
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CHINA_DESCR}Zhao Kuo, Emperor of the Song dynasty\n\nEstimated difficulty: Moderate
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_CHINA_TITLE}River Fully Red
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_DENMARK_DESCR}Veera Ballala II, King of Hoysala\n\nEstimated difficulty: Easy\n\nKannada folklore tells of a man named Sala and his guru Sundatta, who were attacked by a tiger near the temple of Vasantika in Angadi. Sala drew his dagger and slew it, rescuing Sundatta. It is from this tale that Hoysala is named, ("hoy" meaning strike, thus "Sala's strike") and regardless of its veracity, there is no doubt that it lives up to the title. \n\nHoysala has quickly risen as the dominant power in Southern India, and one of the most powerful Hindu kingdoms.\n\nThe Kannada are exceptionally skilled swordsmen, and are experts with the Indian longbow.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_DENMARK_TITLE}Tiger Slayers
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_EGYPT_DESCR}al-Malik al-'Ādil I "Sword of Faith", Sultan of the Ayyubid dynasty\n\nAt a time where religious intolerance is common throughout the known world, Egypt stands out as an enlightened melting pot of religions and ideologies. Descendents of Mohammed's daughter Fatima, the Fatimid rulers of Egypt are Shiite Muslims, but Sunnis, Jews and Christians still hold offices and government positions. Unlike the age of the Pharaoh, bloodline is now considered secondary to ability and talent in Egypt, making it a very progressive and balanced nation. After being assimilated into several empires over the past couple of millennia, the people of the Nile have proven to be culturally flexible and great survivors.\n\nFor all its merits, the Fatimid dynasty was once a little mightier than it is now, with its borders receding after a reign of madness and mismanagement by Caliph Al-Hakim. Fortunately for the Egyptians, none of their neighbours are bearing down upon their lands - in fact, expanding in any direction shouldn't prove a problem. The Moors lie much too far to the west to be considered an immediate threat, and the Holy lands beyond Gaza are presently ruled by petty Sheikhs and Emirs that are backed by none of the major empires.\n\nThough the problems facing the Egyptians close to home aren't anything a decisive ruler can't deal with, any Egyptian forays into the Holy lands will no doubt be subject to Catholic invasion from across the Mediterranean. Regular military pilgrimages by European Christians to Jerusalem seem an inevitability, as do counter-attacks from other Muslim powers such as the Turks. Expand and consolidate quickly and the world could be your oyster.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_EGYPT_TITLE}Defenders of the Faith
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ENGLAND_DESCR}John, King of England\n\nEstimated difficulty: Easy\n\nHaving recently wrestled control of England from the Saxons, many would expect the conquering Normans to be somewhat spent and weakened. However, the new rulers of England have swiftly replaced and improved the taxation system so as to replenish their coffers in quick time. Most importantly, William the Conqueror came with the support of the Pope, as well as a mixed force of well-trained infantry, archers and heavy cavalry. England's new masters have a more modern approach to the art of warfare, and the will to utilise the country's rich resources to maximum effect.\n\nThe English court may now speak French, but the Normans certainly don't consider their new conquest a French territory. This independence in England, plus the proximity of Normandy to other lands the French monarchy consider their own, makes France an immediate and obvious threat to deal with. The ever stubborn Scottish also prevent the King of England from having uncontested control of the British Isles.\n\nThough they presently face trouble on multiple fronts, the English are in a rather promising position. The Scots to the north are isolated from the rest of Europe, and should be easy to wear down without a strong ally from the mainland. The French royal forces are more than a match for the armies in Normandy, but they also have enough fronts to deal with right now that they are unlikely to be able to drive them from the continent anytime soon.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ENGLAND_TITLE}Angevin Empire
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_FRANCE_DESCR}Phillippe II "Augustus", King of the Franks\n\nEstimated difficulty: Moderate\n\nFrance is a shining example of feudalism in its rawest, and arguably, most delicate form. The French lords eagerly embrace the system that splits the country up into smaller provinces, duchies and fiefdoms, actively building up their forces to ensure their own security and power. About the only thing the French lack at this point is a sense of unity...\n\nThe Ile de France may be where the monarchy resides, but the royal family rarely leave Paris. This is not because of a great love for the city, but rather because the surrounding lands are under the shadow of bastions owned by "Robber Barons" that serve their own interests. Frankly, the way things are now, the King isn't truly safe to wander a kingdom that is supposedly his.\n\nThe Normans are clearly serving their own best interests, having recently taken England for themselves, it's hard to believe that they will be content to stop there. Other provinces such as Aquitaine, Burgundy, Brittany and Flanders aren't quite so dangerously ambitious... exercising a little authority over these lands looks like an essential move for the French if they're to have any hope of creating a power base that can stave off the might of the Holy Roman Empire to the east. Even less pressing concerns like Spanish and Milanese expansion will soon become a royal headache for the monarchy if France does not establish solid fronts to the south.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_FRANCE_TITLE}Bastion of Chivalry
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_HRE_DESCR}Friedrich II\nEmperor of the Romans\n\nEstimated difficulty: Moderate\nThe Holy Roman Empire is a particularly misleading name for Europe's largest collective of kingdoms and fiefdoms, regardless which way one looks at it. For starters, it is the empire of Byzantium that truly carries on the legacy of ancient Rome, and the notion that the Kaiser truly serves the Roman Catholic Church is presently quite laughable.\n\nA great rift in opinion exists between Kaiser Henry IV and Pope Gregory VII as to the legitimacy of the Papacy's recent move to do away with secular investiture, a change of law that has taken away all of the Kaiser's power over the Catholic Church. How the Kaiser should react to this is undoubtedly the biggest dilemma facing the Holy Roman Empire at present. When a ruler of nations allows a man of the cloth to dictate what he can and can't do, he sets a bad precedent. Of course, if he leads his people into open conflict with the church itself, he is arguably setting an even worse one.\n\nWith both extremes looking like perilous choices the Kaiser will need to find the best middle ground he can, very much the same situation he faces when looking at his borders. The Empire itself is Europe's middle ground, centrally located, with opportunities to expand in almost every direction, but also potential competition to come with each opportunity. It is a far cry from the days of Charlemagne when all of Western Europe answered to the Emperor. Now France is a separate entity, Italy has become a formidable group of city states, the Danes block the route into Scandinavia and the kingdoms to the east are more of a threat than a place to lay claim to.\n\nShould the Kaiser successfully deal with the dissent that lingers within the Reich at present, there seems no reason the Reich cannot consolidate and expand into something to rival the first Roman Empire... though this time, it won't be a simple matter of bettering the barbarians.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_HRE_TITLE}Imperatores Romanorum
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_HUNGARY_DESCR}László III, King of Hungary\n\nExactly a full millennium since the birth of the Messiah, the Christian Kingdom of Hungary was born when Pope Silvester II sent the "Holy Crown" to signify that the pious noble István I, had become the founding Christian monarch of the realm. Dying without leaving an heir, pagans soon once again assumed control of Hungary, but it would seem this is a land Christendom was destined to call its own. When László recently succeeded his brother Geza I as King of Hungary, he nationalised Christianity so utterly, and with such fervour, that he is already being deemed by many to be a living Saint.\n\nThough it is clear that the Pope's approval of László's unusual piety has no doubt re-established Hungary as a respectable Catholic kingdom, it would appear that the Hungarians will soon be taking on another Christian power should they wish to expand at all. The Holy Roman Empire and Poland essentially cut off all of Hungary's options to the west or north respectively, leaving Moldavia and Wallachia as the paths of least resistance out of the Carpathian mountains.\n\nOf course, to follow such a path is to spoil the plans of the Byzantine Empire to regain its western provinces. Avoiding interfering with Byzantine interests leaves only one other option, sweeping north around the Crimea into the Ukraine. This however, simply replaces one Orthodox adversary with another, and will require immediate action, as the armies of Novgorod are already poised to sweep southward to unite the Russian principalities.\n\nRegardless what László's first move is, nothing will change the fact that Hungary has become Catholicism's physical front line against all other faiths - Something that will doubtlessly bring great glory, yet even greater bloodshed.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_HUNGARY_TITLE}Kingdom of the Magyars
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_INCANS_DESCR}Manqu Qhapaq, King of Qusqu\n\nEstimated difficulty: Easy
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_INCANS_TITLE}Empire of Four Corners
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MALI_DESCR}Naré Maghann Konaté, King of the Mandinka\n\nEstimated difficulty: Moderate
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MALI_TITLE}The Gilded Kings
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MAYANS_DESCR}Hunac Ceel Cauich, Ruler of Mayapan\n\nEstimated difficulty: Moderate\n\nThe Maya of Mesoamerica are not dominated by one ruling aristocracy. Instead, they form many small city-states, each with their own royalty and a large temple for worshipping their gods. The Maya have a long history when compared to their Mexica neighbours, spanning over a millennia, during which the Mayas' riches, power, and territory steadily expanded. \n\nAt their peak, the Maya claim some of the most densely populated and largest settlements in the world, complete with awe-inspiring architecture and advances in science, mathematics, and language. Unfortunately for them, however, the bloody raids of the Mexica are happening further and further both to the north and east, and the Maya may be the next target of their mass human sacrifices. Now is the time to take up arms to preserve the glory of the Kingdom of Q'umarkaj.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MAYANS_TITLE}Warriors of Kukulkan
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MILAN_DESCR}'Alā' al-Din Muhammad II, Shah of Khwarezm\n\nEstimated difficulty: Hard
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MILAN_TITLE}Crossroads of Civilization
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MONGOLS_DESCR}Temüjin, Warlord of the Borjigin clan\n\nEstimated difficulty: ???
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MONGOLS_TITLE}The Blue Wolf
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MOORS_DESCR}Muhammad al-Nasir, Caliph of the Almohad dynasty\n\nEstimated difficulty: Moderate\n\nThe Moors were originally a nomadic people, the original inhabitants of Mauretania on the north coast of Africa. They rose from obscurity in the 8th century when they converted to Islam, and proceeded to spread rapidly in several directions - including north-west into the Iberian peninsula. They soon had almost total dominion over all of Iberia with the exception of the lands to the north where some resilient Christians held fast, but Islamic Spain was a collection of cities more than a true caliphate - until now.\n\nThe Almoravid Berbers have risen from their homelands near the west coast of Africa to establish their capital in Marrakesh, and assume control of the Moorish empire. Their dominance over this corner of Africa is absolute, and the sense of unity they have brought to the Moorish empire has once again restored order in southern Iberia. This move for stable Islamic rule is however also the cause of the greatest threat to the Moors... Christian unity.\n\nOnce weak, uncultured and disorganised, the kingdoms of Leon and Castile are now unified in their challenge against Islamic rule of the peninsula, and look set to actually launch a genuine offensive to revive their Reconquista. Their heroes such as El Cid are extremely admirable adversaries, as men who are driven with what they believe to be a noble purpose always are.\n\nPerhaps the best course of action for the Moors is to play the rulers of Portugal and Castile against one another. So long as they are united in a religious crusade against Islam they are the Moors' greatest threat. Of course, the greed of Christian leaders is something that can be counted upon, and siding with one of these two powers could be possible even if it is undesirable. It is an option they must keep in mind, for expanding too far eastward towards Arabia involves taking on other followers of Islam such as the Egyptians... something most unlikely to be the will of Allah.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MOORS_TITLE}Fortress of Islam
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_NORMANS_DESCR}Minamoto no Sanetomo, Kamakura shōgun\n\nEstimated difficulty: Easy
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_NORMANS_TITLE}Divine Winds
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_PAPAL_STATES_DESCR}Innocentius III, Pontifex maximus\n\nEstimated difficulty: Very easy\n\nPapal States
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_PAPAL_STATES_TITLE}Patrimonium Sancti Petri
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_POLAND_DESCR}Wladyslaw III "Spindleshanks", High duke of Poland\n\nEstimated difficulty: ???\n\nThe Kingdom of Poland is still a relative infant, but an infant that already appears to boast a considerable grip on the lands around the capital of Krakow. The Polish people can attribute their rapid rise out of obscurity to the Drang nach Osten (Drive towards the East) of the Holy Roman Empire, which saw the Kaiser searching for allies to help crush the Polabian Slavs. After converting to Christianity, Boleslaw the Brave saw it as his right and duty to conquer neighbouring lands, including thrusts as far east as Kiev, and even forays into Imperial lands during disputes between the Kaiser and the Pope.\n\nThat last act of betrayal is a sign of recent times in Poland, with internal power struggles stalling the continued expansion of Polish borders. Fortunately for the Poles, the last King to rule with any true sense of stability, Kazimierz I, paved the way for granting fiefdoms to his warriors, establishing a tradition of feudalistic knighthood required to be a power in Europe today.\n\nOnly now is order truly being restored with Wladyslaw Herman taking the throne with his brother being forced into exile. Siding with the Pope in his recent clashes with the Kaiser has helped establish Poland as a legitimate Catholic power, ensuring the Reich can no longer expand eastward with the blessing of Christendom.\n\nHowever, the lack of an immediate Imperial threat does not ensure that the Poles have an easy option to expand either. The Hungarian King László is simply too formidable and familiar with Polish ways to make moving southward a viable option, making securing the lands of the Baltic Sea the most appealing choice... Despite the fact it involves beating the Danes, the Russians and the Reich to the draw. If Poland is to maintain its new status as a genuine power, Wladyslaw must choose his next battle and enemy very carefully.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_POLAND_TITLE}Poles
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_PORTUGAL_DESCR}Afonso II "the Fat", King of Portugal\n\nEstimated difficulty: Hard\n\nOf all of the European royal courts, Portugal is the youngest, having only just recently come of age, growing from county to Kingdom. As is typical at this stage of life, there have been more than a few growing pains for Portugal, and its inaugural King, Afonso Henrique. As if being recognised as the sovereign of a land were not hard enough at the best of times, Afonso's own mother attempted to seize power for herself before he was forced to defeat and then exile her!\n\nAs grim as Portugal's first years have been, there is no doubting that these shameful acts of betrayal within his own family have ensured that Afonso is a true survivor - and only a man that has endured through such troubles is likely to turn his fledgling Kingdom into a western power. Portugal's greatest threat does not lie within however...\n\nDespite some of the Kings and Emirs of the Iberian Peninsula supporting religious tolerance, the Christian and Islamic faiths do not appear to be able to share these lands peacefully. The ongoing Reconquista seems almost certain to ensure that the Moors will be an enemy of Portugal, at least until they are driven back across the straits of Gibraltar. That said, even then they will still be an immediate threat.\n\nThe other obvious threat is that of Alfonso el Valiente. No matter how noble he may be, any man who would declare himself Emperor of Spain essentially declares himself the rightful ruler of all of Iberia. It is entirely possible that he will seek to once again make Portugal a mere county to offer in his political barter.\n\nSome of the Portuguese believe that the best tyranny to face is that of distance. Poised on the edge of the civilised world, perhaps Portugal's fortunes lie across the seas and oceans, rather than across her immediate borders.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_PORTUGAL_TITLE}Portugal
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_RUSSIA_DESCR}???, Grand Prince of Kiev\n\nEstimated difficulty: Easy\n\nThe Rus' are a people divided, though that is hardly a character judgement for the folk who live in the largest single kingdom in Europe. Kiev may actually be the royal capital of this Kingdom, and the site where the Rus' embraced Christianity, but it is far to the north that the true power of the realm currently lies. Positioned just off the eastern end of the Baltic Sea, Novgorod is presently one of the most important trade hubs in the region, while in Kiev, disputes over succession have destroyed any sense of organisation or unity.\n\nWith the royal court in Kiev in such disarray, it would seem that any immediate military campaigns should be launched from around the trade capital of Novgorod. In fact, the first order for Vsevolod, Grand Duke of Kiev is to re-assert his undisputed control all the way down to the capital to the south. Should he manage this, the Rus' will be free to unify all of the steppes into the mightiest power of the east.\n\nSimple and obvious in principle, this plan will require swift and decisive action. The fledgling kingdoms of Poland and Hungary to the southwest are just as well placed to move and assume control of the Rus' capital. Byzantium to the south is also desperate to restore its former glory by taking new territories, and it was only through Vsevolod's marriage to the Byzantine princess Maria that prevented the empire from striking back at the Rus' after they failed in their assault of Constantinople. They will not forget that they defeated the Rus' so recently...\n\nThis is not something that the present Rus' army should forget either. Unless they can start recruiting from several population centres at once again, they will not be able to field a force capable of stopping any of the serious foreign powers at all.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_RUSSIA_TITLE}Estimated difficulty: ???
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_RYUKYU_DESCR}Lý Cao Tông, Emperor of the Lý dynasty\n\nEstimated difficulty: Hard\n\nThe lush jungles and fertile paddies of Vietnam are home to a proud and fiercely independent people. For much of the past millennia, these lands were under Chinese dominion, broken up by revolts and brief periods of self-rule before the Vietnamese firmly established a true kingdom of their own by 968. After a failed invasion in 981, the Song dynasty of China was finally forced to acknowledge the sovereignty of Dai Viet's kings.\n\nAlthough small, Dai Viet has already demonstrated its potential to become a major regional power. Another Song excursion was driven back in 1077, as were multiple Khmer invasions throughout the 12th century. At the present, Dai Viet is not immediately under threat and is well-positioned to begin expanding its territory. However, doing so will certainly draw attention from other powers.\n\nHeading for the Cham lands is sure to provoke the ambitious Thai, who already seek to dominate the south. Meanwhile, conquering Dali to the north would mean once again sharing a border with China. Though the Song may be at peace with Dai Viet and currently occupied with threats further north, the already strained relations between the two would surely reinvigorate their historic feud. Or perhaps, the horse nomads raiding China's northern borders may be an even greater threat than anything the Vietnamese have faced before...\n\nOwing to their unique history and geographic position, the Vietnamese army uses an intriguing blend of Southeast Asian tactics with Chinese-style equipment and discipline. Vietnamese soldiers are more heavily armoured than their counterparts throughout the subcontinent and have developed a strong affinity for the crossbow. Although they field rather weak cavalry, it is arguably made up for by their contingents of war elephants!
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_RYUKYU_TITLE}Rising Dragon
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SAXONS_DESCR}Wanyan Jing, Emperor of the Jin dynasty\n\nEstimated difficulty: Very hard
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SAXONS_TITLE}Horsemen of the Gold River
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SCOTLAND_DESCR}Unknown emperor of the Zā dynasty\n\nEstimated difficulty: Easy
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SCOTLAND_TITLE}Horselords of the Sahel
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SICILY_DESCR}Sri Naonumthum, Lord of Sukhothai\n\nEstimated difficulty: Moderate
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SICILY_TITLE}Thailand
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SPAIN_DESCR}Alfonso VIII, King of Castile\n\nEstimated difficulty: Moderate\n\nAny man who is born on the Iberian Peninsula would call himself a "Spaniard", so when King Alfonso VI declared himself the "Emperor of all Spain" three years ago, it was a truly bold claim. After all, not since the times of the Western Roman Empire has one noble court truly ruled the peninsula unopposed. Currently, the Moors hold southern Iberia quite tightly, and Portugal's declaration of independence really proves Alfonso wrong.\n\nHowever, Alfonso has managed to become the King of Leon, Castile and Galicia all at once, so there is definitely more to his claim than wild boasts. Now that the petty differences of the Christian courts have been abolished, the Reconquista looks like it may finally become a reality - Alfonso VI is the first sovereign to truly find himself in a position to actually drive the Muslims back into northern Africa.\n\nThe first moves for the King of Spain are obvious, but beyond Iberia, there is far less certainty. The King of France may be cowering in Paris to avoid facing other French noble robber barons, but crossing the Pyranees to take his southern fiefdoms is more likely to unify his people than split their loyalties.\n\nUnless the new Spanish royalty are willing to embark on such a dangerous campaign, they must look to the sea to find less daunting borders to cross. The Spaniards have always shown an affinity for the water, and make fine seafarers. Who knows, perhaps the great empires of the future will be forged at sea rather than on dry land - If so, the people who mastered this art of war first would inherit the earth.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SPAIN_TITLE}Los Reconquistadores
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TIMURIDS_DESCR}Mu'izz al-Dīn Muḥammad ibn Sām "Second Alexander", Sultan of Ghor\n\nEstimated difficulty: Hard\n\nHindustanis
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TIMURIDS_TITLE}Gateway to India
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TITLE}Grand Campaign
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TURKS_DESCR}Kaykhusraw ibn Kilij Arslān, Claimant to Sultan of Rûm\n\nEstimated difficulty: Easy\n\nThe Seljuk Turks may very much be relative newcomers to both Anatolia and the Holy Lands, but the impact that they have had upon these realms since they migrated from the steppes east of the Caspian has been profound enough to shake the pillars of the oldest and mightiest neighbouring dynasties. Having seized control of the Abbasid Caliphate from the Buyids, and utterly crushed the Byzantines at Manzikert, the Turks have restored unity to the eastern Islamic region, making them arguably the greatest power Arabia or Persia has seen for centuries.\n\nSettling down has been the Turks' secret to asserting their dominion. Traditionally a nomadic people, they have at last adopted a system of centralised rule to form the Seljuk Empire. Considering they have relied upon their natural skill at mounted combat and guerrilla warfare for centuries, the Turks have already shown incredible talent at governing a vast empire from a single throne.\n\nIn the foreseeable future, arrogance and complacency are likely to be the biggest threats to the mighty Seljuk Empire. To expect Byzantium to underestimate Turkish forces after the slaughter of Manzikert would be folly, and it can be taken as given that they will attempt to regain control of Anatolia. It would also be foolish to believe that the Fatimid dynasty in Egypt will be content to simply overlook the fertile banks of the Nile - They are just as well placed to seize control of all of the Holy Lands.\n\nSo long as the Turks manage to combine their new system of centralised government with their innate abilities as mounted warriors, then their position in this corner of the world looks most secure. After all, how likely is it that an even more fierce and formidable race of nomadic warriors sweep down from the steppes?
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TURKS_TITLE}Estimated difficulty: ???
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_VENICE_DESCR}Huijong, King of Goryeo\n\nEstimated difficulty: Very hard
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_VENICE_TITLE}Morning Radiance
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ZIMBABWE_DESCR}Gebre Meskel Lalibela, King of the Zagwe dynasty\n\nEstimated difficulty: Moderate\n\nFrom the highlands of Ethiopia emerged one of the world's oldest Christian kingdoms. The kingdom of Aksum rose as the dominant power in Africa during the classical period, becoming incredibly wealthy from trade routes across the Indian Ocean. In fact, in the 3rd century, Sassanian prophet Mani declared Aksum to be one of the world's four great powers, alongside Persia, China, and Rome.\n\nThis golden age was not to last, unfortunately. As the other great powers waned, Aksum, reliant on their commerce, fell into a centuries long dark age. After its destruction in 960 at the hands of Queen Yodit, the southern dynasty of Zagwe was left as the sole inheritor of its legacy. The victories of Nubian Makuria over the Rashidun caliphs at Dongola have prevented these lands from falling under Islamic rule, allowing the Christians of East Africa to persevere for now. However, the treaty of baqt, though upheld for nearly 600 years, was never an alliance and is certainly not an end to Arab ambitions. With the sultans of Egypt growing in strength while the kingdoms of Nubia begin to decline, it is now up to the Ethiopians to re-emerge from obscurity and reclaim their past glory.\n\nEthiopians have had a reputation as fierce fighters since ancient times, with the deeds of king Memnon during the Trojan War being celebrated well beyond Africa. They are most proficient with two traditional weapons: the shotel sword and two-handed lutat. Ethiopians are also capable with the longbow, and can count on the renowned pupil-smiters of Nubia.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ZIMBABWE_TITLE}Lions of Judah
{NORMAN_PROLOGUE_NORMANS_DESCR}If this text is visible, something has gone horribly wrong.
{NORMAN_PROLOGUE_NORMANS_TITLE}If this text is visible, something has gone horribly wrong.
{NORMAN_PROLOGUE_TITLE}If this text is visible, something has gone horribly wrong.
