¬
{Author_1}Arnaud Amaury, Abbot of Citeaux
{Author_10}Robert Guiscard 
{Author_100}Matthew of Edessa
{Author_102}Laonikos Chalkokondyles, The Histories
{Author_103}Konrad III, King of Germany
{Author_104}Bernard of Clairvaux
{Author_105}Laonikos Chalkokondyles, The Histories
{Author_106}Genghis Khan
{Author_107}Archbishop Hugh
{Author_108}Il-Ghazi
{Author_109}Walter, Chancellor to Roger of Salerno
{Author_11}Italian proverb
{Author_110}William of Tyre
{Author_111}Adela, wife of Stephen of Blois
{Author_112}Bohemund
{Author_113}Anna Komnene, The Alexiad 
{Author_114}Fulcher of Chartres
{Author_115}Fulcher of Chartres
{Author_116}Fulcher of Chartres
{Author_117}Trần Hưng Đạo
{Author_118}William of Apulia
{Author_119}Bernard of Clairvaux
{Author_12}Sun Tzu, The Art of War
{Author_120}Orderic Vitalis
{Author_13}Martin Luther 
{Author_14}Subotai to Genghis Khan
{Author_15}Battle standard of Takeda Shingen
{Author_16}Martin Luther
{Author_17}Niccolò Machiavelli
{Author_18}Niccolò Machiavelli
{Author_19}Niccolò Machiavelli
{Author_2}Francis Bacon 
{Author_20}Niccolò Machiavelli
{Author_21}Niccolò Machiavelli
{Author_22}Niccolò Machiavelli
{Author_23}Niccolò Machiavelli
{Author_24}Niccolò Machiavelli
{Author_25}Niccolò Machiavelli
{Author_26}Genghis Khan
{Author_27}Niccolò Machiavelli
{Author_29}Niccolò Machiavelli
{Author_3}Thomas Aquinas
{Author_30}Niccolò Machiavelli
{Author_31}Niccolò Machiavelli
{Author_32}Niccolò Machiavelli
{Author_33}Niccolò Machiavelli
{Author_34}Niccolò Machiavelli
{Author_35}Christopher Marlowe 
{Author_36}John Milton
{Author_37}Cao Cao
{Author_38}Genghis Khan
{Author_39}Oda Nobunaga
{Author_4}Tamerlane
{Author_40}John Milton
{Author_41}John Milton
{Author_42}Constantine XI
{Author_43}Henry V
{Author_44}Sanada Nobushige
{Author_45}Shakespeare, As You Like It, v, 1
{Author_46}Shakespeare, King John, iii, 1
{Author_47}Shakespeare, Hamlet, iv, 2 
{Author_48}Shakespeare, King John, iv, 7
{Author_49}Shakespeare, King Henry IV, Part:II. iii, 2
{Author_5}Yelu Chucai
{Author_50}Shakespeare, King Richard III, v, 3
{Author_51}Minamoto Yorimasa
{Author_52}Shakespeare, King Henry IV, Part:I, v, 4
{Author_53}Shakespeare, King Henry the Sixth, Part:III, ii, 5
{Author_54}Shakespeare, Much Ado About Nothing, i, 1 
{Author_55}Shakespeare, King Henry IV, Part:II, iv, 2
{Author_56}Shakespeare, King Henry VI, Part:III, ii, 1
{Author_57}Shakespeare, King Henry V, iv prologue
{Author_58}Shakespeare, Macbeth, II, 3
{Author_59}Tamerlane
{Author_6}Erasmus
{Author_60}Matthew, ch. XXIV, V.6
{Author_61}Psalm, CXLIV
{Author_64}Moslih Eddin Saadi
{Author_65}Gabriel Biel
{Author_66}Fredrick I, Barbarossa
{Author_67}Niccolò Machiavelli
{Author_68}Mitsuhide Akechi
{Author_69}Genghis Khan
{Author_7}Erasmus
{Author_71}Michel Eyquem de Montaigne
{Author_72}Michel Eyquem de Montaigne
{Author_73}Michel Eyquem de Montaigne
{Author_74}Louis XI, King of France
{Author_75}Jacobus de Benedictus
{Author_76}Petrarch
{Author_78}Friedrich II, Holy Roman Emperor
{Author_79}Miyamoto Musashi
{Author_8}Erasmus
{Author_80}Moslih Eddin Saadi
{Author_81}Saint Anselm, Archbishop of Canterbury
{Author_82}Genghis Khan
{Author_83}Genghis Khan
{Author_84}Welsh proverb
{Author_85}Urban II, Pope
{Author_86}Gian Jacopo Trivulzio
{Author_87}Shakespeare, King Henry VI, part 1, i, 1
{Author_88}Shakespeare, Macbeth, v, 3
{Author_89}Shakespeare, King Henry V, iii, 1
{Author_9}Gerard of Ridefort, letter written to King Guy 
{Author_92}Luis Camões, The Lusíads, canto 1:15
{Author_93}Spanish conquistador
{Author_94}Genghis Khan
{Author_95}Alfonso X the Wise, King of Castile
{Author_96}Basileios II
{Author_98}Pope Urban II
{Author_99}Lý Thường Kiệt
{Quote_1}"Kill them all. God will recognise his own."
{Quote_10}"The strength of God will enable us, a small but faithful band, to overcome the multitude of the faithless."
{Quote_100}"The fighting was fierce and lasted for the greater part of a day; blood ran in rivers."
{Quote_102}"Vlad fought bravely, routed and captured...and killed a few of those who fled. After capturing them, he led them all away to be impaled, but first he cut off the men's limbs."
{Quote_103}"Let anyone who has zeal for God come with me! Let us fight for our brothers! Let Heaven's will be done!"
{Quote_104}"God has aroused the spirit of kings and princes to root up from the earth the enemies of the Christian name."
{Quote_105}"The Turks were dumbfounded when they saw the multitude of men on the stakes...birds had made their nests in their entrails."
{Quote_106}"All who surrender will be spared; whoever does not surrender but opposes with struggle and dissension shall be annihilated."
{Quote_107}"We shall not surrender."
{Quote_108}"Come on soldiers! Guardians and agents of the supreme law! Here is a sacrifice of dogs ready for your swords!"
{Quote_109}"At the first sound of the bugle, everyone should make haste to put on arms and armour."
{Quote_11}"It is better to live one day as a lion than a hundred years as a sheep."
{Quote_110}"Put an end to so great an evil and arrive at a peace settlement whatever the outcome, and whatever the conditions."
{Quote_111}"Take up the weapons of the glorious army for the salvation of many thousands."
{Quote_112}"If they wish to fight today, let them come like men."
{Quote_113}"They assembled from all sides, one after another, with arms and horses and all the panoply of war..."
{Quote_114}"Alas! How many noble and valiant knights we lost."
{Quote_115}"There is now no hope of escaping. If you fight you will conquer, but if you flee you will fall."
{Quote_116}"When he caught sight of their army, he was terrified and groaned in his mind."
{Quote_117}"Every century has produced heroes who have sacrificed their lives for their country. If they had remained at home...would their names have been inscribed on bamboo and silk to live eternally in heaven and on the Earth?"
{Quote_118}"He withdrew, himself wounded, and was compelled to return home inglorious, weeping - he who had once vainly hoped for the glory of a triumph."
{Quote_119}"Therefore gird yourselves manfully and take up joyful arms for the name of Christ."
{Quote_12}"All warfare is based on deception."
{Quote_120}"Set out on pilgrimage and triumph gloriously over the infidels in the East."
{Quote_13}"A safe stronghold our God is still. A trusty shield and weapon."
{Quote_14}"I will ward off your enemies as felt cloth protects one from the wind."
{Quote_15}"Swift as the wind, silent as the forest, fierce as fire, unshakable as the mountain."
{Quote_16}"War is the greatest plague that can affect humanity; it destroys religion, it destroys states, it destroys families. Any scourge is preferable to it."
{Quote_17}"Since love and fear can hardly coexist together, if we must choose between them, it is far safer to be feared than loved."
{Quote_18}"The princes who have done great things are the ones who have taken little account of their promises."
{Quote_19}"So far as he is able, a prince should stick to the path of good but, if the necessity arises, he should know how to follow evil."
{Quote_2}"Nothing is to be feared but fear."
{Quote_20}"Men should either be treated generously or destroyed, because they take revenge for slight injures - for heavy ones they cannot."
{Quote_21}"The prince must be a fox... to recognize the traps and a lion to frighten the wolves."
{Quote_22}"The sinews of war are not gold, but good soldiers."
{Quote_23}"Among other evils which being unarmed brings you, it causes you to be despised."
{Quote_24}"The best fortress which a prince can possess is the affection of his people."
{Quote_25}"No enterprise is more likely to succeed than one concealed from the enemy until it is ripe for execution."
{Quote_26}"One arrow alone can be easily broken, but many arrows are indestructible."
{Quote_27}"Whoever conquers a free town and does not demolish it commits a great error and may expect to be ruined himself."
{Quote_29}"Good order and discipline in any army are to be depended upon more than courage alone."
{Quote_3}"In order for a war to be just, three things are necessary. First, the authority of the sovereign. Secondly, a just cause. Thirdly, a rightful intention."
{Quote_30}"Good order makes men bold, and confusion, cowards."
{Quote_31}"He who wishes to be obeyed must know how to command."
{Quote_32}"One should never risk one's whole fortune unless supported by one's entire forces."
{Quote_33}"It is not titles that honour men, but men that honour titles."
{Quote_34}"To ensure victory the troops must have confidence in themselves as well as in their commanders."
{Quote_35}"Strike up the drum and march courageously."
{Quote_36}"Better to reign in hell than serve in heav'n."
{Quote_37}"I am in charge of the battle, not them! They may be skilled in using long spears, but I will make them unable to use their spears."
{Quote_38}"The greatest happiness is to vanquish your enemies, to chase them before you, to rob them of their wealth, to see those dear to them bathed in tears..."
{Quote_39}"Do you really want to spend your entire lives praying for longevity? We were born in order to die!  Whoever is with me, come to the battlefield tomorrow morning. Whoever is not, just stay wherever you are and watch me win it!"
{Quote_4}"Just as there is but one lord in heaven, there ought to be but one ruler on Earth."
{Quote_40}"Peace hath her victories, no less renowned than War."
{Quote_41}"What does not destroy me, makes me strong. "
{Quote_42}"Present your shield, swords, arrows, and spears to them...so that the impious may learn that they are dealing not with dumb animals but with their lords and masters, the descendants of Greece and Rome!"
{Quote_43}"War has three handmaidens: fire, blood, and famine."
{Quote_44}"I am Sanada Nobushige, no doubt a worthy adversary, but I am tired and can fight no longer. Go on, take my head as your prize."
{Quote_45}"I will kill thee a hundred and fifty ways."
{Quote_46}"Here I and sorrows sit; Here is my throne, bid kings come bow to it."
{Quote_47}"Go, bid the soldiers shoot."
{Quote_48}"Come the three corners of the world in arms, and we shall shock them."
{Quote_49}"A man can die but once."
{Quote_5}"Conquering the world on horseback is easy. It is dismounting and governing that is hard."
{Quote_50}"Give me another horse: bind up my wounds."
{Quote_51}"Like a rotten log, half buried in the ground; My life, which has not flowered, comes to this sad end."
{Quote_52}"The better part of valour is discretion."
{Quote_53}"To whom God will, there be the victory."
{Quote_54}"A victory is twice itself when the achiever brings home full numbers."
{Quote_55}"We are ready to try our fortunes To the last man."
{Quote_56}"And many strokes, though with a little axe, hew down and fell the hardest-timbered oak."
{Quote_57}"Upon his royal face there is no note how dread an army hath enrounded him."
{Quote_58}"There's daggers in men's smiles."
{Quote_59}"It is better to be on hand with ten men than absent with ten thousand."
{Quote_6}"War is delightful to those who have had no experience of it."
{Quote_60}"And ye shall hear of wars and rumours of wars, see that ye be not troubled; for all these things must come to pass, but the end is not yet."
{Quote_61}"Blessed be the Lord my strength, which teacheth my hands to war, and my fingers to fight."
{Quote_64}"Inflict not on an enemy every injury in your power, for he may afterwards become your friend."
{Quote_65}"No one conquers who doesn't fight."
{Quote_66}"An emperor is subject to no one but God and justice."
{Quote_67}"Wars begin when you will, but they do not end when you please."
{Quote_68}"The enemy awaits at Honnō-ji!"
{Quote_69}"There is no value in anything until it is finished."
{Quote_7}"Fortune favours the audacious."
{Quote_71}"There are some defeats more triumphant than victories."
{Quote_72}"Tis so much to be a king, that he only is so by being so."
{Quote_73}"The souls of emperors and cobblers are cast in the same mould... The same reason that makes us wrangle with a neighbour causes a war betwixt princes."
{Quote_74}"He who knows not how to dissimulate, can not reign."
{Quote_75}"So many great nobles, things, administrations, so many high chieftains, so many brave nations, so many proud princes, and power so splendid; In a moment, a twinkling, all utterly ended."
{Quote_76}"It is more honourable to be raised to a throne than to be born to one. Fortune bestows the one, merit obtains the other."
{Quote_78}"He who defends everything defends nothing."
{Quote_79}"If you do not control the enemy, the enemy will control you."
{Quote_8}"The most disadvantageous peace is better than the most just war."
{Quote_80}"When you see contention amongst your enemies, go and sit at ease with your friends; but when you see them of one mind, string your bow, and place stones upon the ramparts."
{Quote_81}"Disasters teach us humility."
{Quote_82}"Walls are no stronger than the men that defend them."
{Quote_83}"I am the flail of God! Had you not committed great sins, God would not have sent a punishment like me upon you."
{Quote_84}"In a fight, anger is as good as courage."
{Quote_85}"Undertake this journey for the remission of your sins, with the assurance of the imperishable glory of the Kingdom of Heaven!"
{Quote_86}"To carry on war, three things are necessary: money, money, and yet more money."
{Quote_87}"Fight to the last gasp."
{Quote_88}"I'll fight, till from my bones my flesh be hacked."
{Quote_89}"Once more unto the breach, dear friends, once more!"
{Quote_9}"If you do not leave this pasturage, Saladin will come and attack you here. And if you retreat from this attack the shame and reproach will be very great."
{Quote_92}"Let the world tremble as it senses all you are about to accomplish."
{Quote_93}"If a Mexican is fighting alone, he knows how to retreat, turn back, and rush forward and conquer, even if his opponents are ten or even twenty."
{Quote_94}"It is not sufficient that I succeed. All others must fail!"
{Quote_95}"Had I been present at the creation, I would have given some useful hints for the better ordering of the universe."
{Quote_96}"Whoever is a soldier, follow me!"
{Quote_98}"Let those who once fought against brothers and relatives now rightfully fight against barbarians."
{Quote_99}"How dare these barbarians invade our land? Their armies, without mercy, will be annihilated."
